Finding Aid for Salmon Crane family papers, 1838-1975
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Salmon Crane family papers 1838-1975 1838-1883
Crane, Salmon, 1812-1888.
1 linear foot
851113 Aa 2
Tecumseh, Michigan, builder; account books and miscellaneous family papers.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was the gift of Theodore Crane (donor no. 1005 ).
No further additions to the papers are expected.
The collection is open to research.
Salmon Crane was a building and businessman from Tecumseh, Michigan.
The collection consists of account books of Salmon Crane's business activities, including a ledger previously used for the accounts, 1838-1841, of Spafford and Smith, Tecumseh merchants, and as day book, 1857-1858, of the Tecumseh Herald newspaper. In addition, there are miscellaneous papers of Crane's sons, Theodore H. and Eugene W. Crane, both soldiers in Co. E, 18th Michigan Infantry during the Civil War. Other family members represented in the collection include Charles S. and Verner B. Crane. Photographer Walker Evans was the great-grandson of Salmon Crane.
Subjects:
Business records.; Construction industry.; General stores--Michigan--Tecumseh.; Lenawee County (Mich.); American newspapers--Michigan--Tecumseh.; Spafford and Smith (Merchants: Tecumseh, Mich.); Tecumseh (Mich.); Tecumseh herald.; United States. Army. Michigan Infantry Regiment, 18th (1862-1865). Company E.; United States--History--Civil War, 1861-1865.
Contributors:
Crane, Charles Samuel, 1847-1922.; Crane, Eugene W., 1842-1873.; Crane, Theodore Horace, 1844-1924.; Crane, Verner Brown, 1852-1898.
- Salmon Crane papers
  - Invitations, 1839-1840 (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous financial material (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence and specifications (Box 1)
  - Daybook, 1863 previously used as account book, 1838-1841 of Spafford and Smith, Tecumseh merchants, and as day book, 1857-1858 of the Tecumseh Herald newspaper. (Box 1)
  - Account books
    - 1840-1864 (Box 1)
    - 1864-1866 (Box 1)
    - 1866-1868 (Box 1)
    - 1869-1874 (Box 1)
    - 1874-1880 (Box 1)
    - 1881-1883 (Box 1)
- Other family members
  - Theodore H. Crane
    - Civil War letters, 1862-1865 (Box 1)
    - Account books, 1872-1873 and undated (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence (Box 1)
  - Eugene W. Crane papers (Box 1)
  - Charles S. Crane papers (Box 1)
  - Verner B. Crane papers (Box 1)
  - Chadwick family papers (Box 1)
  - Walker Evans miscellanea (Box 1)
    (great-grandson of Salmon Crane)